(Swoff)
A story.
A man fires a rifle
for many years...
and he goes to war.
And afterward,
he turns the rifle in
at the armory...
and he believes
he's finished with the rifle.
But no matter what else
he might do with his hands...
love a woman, build a house...
change his son's diaper...
his hands remember the rifle.
(Fitch)
You are no longer black,
or brown, or yellow or red!
You are now green!
You are light green
or dark green!
Do you understand?
(all)
Sir, yes, sir!
Swofford!
You the maggot whose father
served in Vietnam?
Sir, yes, sir!
Outstanding!
Did he have the balls
to die there?
Sir, no, sir!
Too fucking bad!
He ever talk about it?
Sir, only once, sir!
Good! Then he wasn't lying!
Are you eyeballing me
with those baby blues?
Are you?
Sir, no, sir!
Are you in love
with me, Swofford?
Sir, no, sir!
You don't think I look good
in my uniform, Swofford?
Sir, the drill sergeant
looks fabulous
in his uniform, sir!
So you're gay, then,
and you love me, huh?
Sir, I'm not gay, sir!
Do you have
a girlfriend, Swofford?
Sir, yes, sir!
Guess again, motherfucker!
Jody's banging her right now!
Get on your face
and give me 25...
for every time
she gets fucked this month.
Down on your face!
(Swoff)
It was shortly after meeting
Drill Instructor Fitch...
that I realized that joining
the Marine Corps...
might have been
a bad decision.
What in the fuck
is this?
Sir,
it's a recruit's drawing
of a footlocker, sir!
Jesus, Joseph
and doggie-style Mary!
That is a pile
of dog shit.
Sir, the recruit's
never been good
at drawing, sir!
Why the fuck
are you my scribe, then?
Isn't my scribe
supposed to know
how to draw?
Sir, the recruit
doesn't know!
The recruit thought
the scribe was supposed
to write, sir!
Of course the recruit
doesn't know!
The recruit doesn't know
because I haven't told him!
[Groaning]
All right,
cum-for-brains...
show me exactly
where your Skivvies
and running shoes go.
Sir, the recruit
can't think...
while the drill instructor
is hitting him
on his head, sir!
You can't think
while I'm giving you
a few love taps?
How the fuck
are you going to
fire your rifle...
when grenades are going off
in your face?
What the fuck
are you even doing here?
Sir, I got lost
on the way to college, sir!
##[Don't Worry Be Happy
playing]
(Swoff)
So, now my hands
were dick skinners.
A flashlight was a moonbeam.
A pen was an ink stick.
My mouth was a cum receptacle.
A bed was a rack.
A wall was a bulkhead.
A shirt was a blouse.
A tie was still a tie,
and a belt a belt.
But many other things
would never be the same.
[Marines sounding off]
Swofford. What kind of
fucking name is that?
It's English.
My great-grandfather
came over here
in the 19th century.
Whatever.
I'm putting you
in Golf Company.
It's full of retards
and fuck ups.
Maybe you can elevate
the sons of bitches a little.
Or maybe not.
Next.
[Marines chattering]
(Swoff)
Jarhead: Noun.
Slang for "Marine."
Origin:
From the resemblance
to a jar...
of the regulation
high-and-tight haircut.
The Marine's head,
by implication, therefore...
also a jar.
An empty vessel.
[Marines exclaiming]
Hey!
May I help you?
Yeah, I was assigned
to Second Platoon.
Second Platoon?
Yeah.
What's going on, boss?
Nothing much, man.
Welcome to Second Platoon.
Thanks, man.
Hey, boys!
Fresh fucking meat!
What kind of meat?
We don't want you!
[Grunting]
Boo, motherfucker!
[Marines hooting]
Get some!
[Groaning]
Oh, fuck.
[Gun clicking]
Yeah, we switched out
the hot brand.
Little fuck-fuck trick
we play on the new guys.
[Gun clicking]
Nice.
You want a brand,
you gotta earn it.
Welcome to the Suck.
[Sighing]
(Nurse)
Still got
that stomach flu, Swofford?
I can't seem to shake it.
That's all right.
Not everyone's cut out
for the Marines.
(Swoff)
But for me, there was nowhere
else. That was the truth.
After all,
I was made in a war.
Here's Mr. And Mrs. Swofford
on R&R from Vietnam.
Honolulu Hilton, 1969.
I can't watch...
and neither can you.
And here are some other things
I can't show you.
Visiting my sister.
[Sobbing]
Making muffins with Mom.
Breakfast conversations
with Dad.
But here are some things
you can see.
Taking a dump.
Thinking about
going to college.
Studying after school
with my girlfriend.
Oh, my God, I love you.
I love you, too.
Giving away
my favorite USMC T-shirt.
I'll write you every day.
(Staff Sgt. Sykes)
Hey!
Swofford?
Yo.
What the fuck? You're sick?
No, I just had
a stomach thing, sir.
Staff Sergeant Sykes.
I'm with Surveillance
and Target Acquisition. STA.
I heard it took six guys
to pull that little branding
trick on you.
Your file says that you ain't
too fucking dumb, either.
So you better get un-sick
most motherfucking
ricky-tick...
because there's a chance
that you could be
a scout sniper.
What the fuck is this?
"The Stranger by Camus."
That's some heavy dope
right there, Marine.
"Mary however..."
"That's when we ran up
to the office..."
Indoc class starts on Monday.
I suggest you have
your ass there.
Is that an order,
Staff Sergeant?
It's a fucking opportunity.
It's a fucking honor.
It's the best fucking job
in the Marine Corps.
Sounds good, Staff Sergeant.
Sounds good,
Staff Sergeant!
Sounds good.
Could I have my...
You know what?
I got a better idea.
You play any instruments?
I played the trumpet
in third grade,
Staff Sergeant.
Played the trumpet
in third grade? Good.
You still play?
A little,
for small holiday concerts
and festivals.
Good. You ain't gotta be
Chuck Mangione.
All I need is a bugler.
Somebody to play Taps,
Reveille, Battle March...
that type of shit,
raise the morale.
Does that interest you?
Oh, yeah.
Good! Parade field, 0600.
All right, thank you,
Staff Sergeant!
My pleasure.
Can I get my book?
[Trash can rattling]
There's 60 of you.
I only need eight.
That means 52 of you
will perish. Do the math.
There's no possible way
that all of you can make it.
If you think
you're worth some shit...
Staff Sergeant Sykes!
Private Swofford
reporting for bugle tryout!
Indoc! Atten-hut!
I don't give out
too many special treats...
but this morning,
we have a very special treat.
Private Swofford here
is going to play Reveille
for us.
Okay, Swofford,
play Reveille.
[Whispering]
I don't have a bugle,
Staff Sergeant.
[Whispering]
You don't have a what?
I don't have a bugle.
Oh, no. No, no.
Damn, damn.
You better play
with your mouth.
What?
I said, play it
with your goddamn mouth.
##[Imitating bugle]
Fuck.
I love that tone.
Sounds good to me.
My morale is lifted.
You know
any Stevie Wonder?
You know You Are
The Sunshine Of My Life?
Yes, Staff Sergeant.
Good, that's a classic.
[Clears throat]
##[Imitating bugle]
[Sykes snapping fingers]
Will you shut the fuck up?
There is no bugle program.
You sizzle-dick motherfucker.
Who do you think you are,
some kind of Kenny G
or some shit?
No, Staff Sergeant.
Good.
Now to the rest of you,
do you have what it takes...
to be the meanest,
the cruelest,
the most savage...
unforgiving motherfuckers
in God's cruel kingdom?
(all)
Yes, Staff Sergeant!
Will you be able to one day
say, "Yea, though I walk...
"through the valley
of the shadow of death,
I will fear no evil...
"because I am
the baddest motherfucker
in the goddamn valley"?
(all)
Yes, Staff Sergeant!
We shall fucking see!
You still here?
Yes, Staff Sergeant!
Yes, what?
Yes, I am still here,
Staff Sergeant.
So fucking be it. Fall in!
One mile!
(all)
Ain't shit!
Two miles!
(Sykes)
Your mission is to kill me.
My mission
is to kill you first,
and I'm good.
Them paintball bullets,
they hurt?
[Groaning]
Oh, shit! Fuck, I can't see!
Back to the grunts, dick face!
(Sykes)
In order to
engage your target...
you must see your target,
but your target
must not see you.
Shevitz.
[All laughing]
You laugh, you die.
Scratch your nose, you die.
You shift your weight
to take a piss, you will die.
You want to shit,
you better shit
in your pants.
(Sykes)
Still kind of cute,
huh, Swoff?
No, sir.
This suit will hide you.
You will become a tree.
A rock.
You are mud, sand, and dust.
Still funny?
No, sir.
In order to fire accurately...
you must be able to judge
distance and wind direction.
How far are those trees?
(Swoff)
500 yards.
No.
(Jocko)
600. (Troy)
300.
300. How did you
figure that?
Three football fields.
Three football fields,
that's right.
You take what you know
and then you multiply.
Please don't use
your dicks.
They're too small,
and I can't count that high.
I don't wanna hear,
"400,000 inches."
Now, wind.
You use what you have.
Use a flag,
use a plume of smoke,
a little bit of dust.
Spit on your finger
and hold that bitch up.
These are formulas
that you can use...
but in the end,
you have to trust your gut.
Details, gentlemen.
Details is gonna be
the difference between
you killing your target...
and your target killing you.
We've all been taught that,
"Thou shalt not kill."
But hear this:
Fuck that shit!
Now, consider your target.
If you are lucky,
in that window
will one day emerge...
the figure of the enemy.
The JFK shot.
The pink mist.
(Troy)
Fire, fire, fire.
Hit.
[Gunfire]
(Sykes)
The sounds that you
are hearing are live rounds.
You will get
the fear out of you.
Keep moving.
If you pick your head up,
you will get fucked up!
Let's find out
if we have any bitch in you!
[Gunfire]
You guys crawl
like old people fuck!
Keep moving!
Get the fear out of you.
Do not bunch up!
Keep moving!
I can't!
[Gasping]
Keep your head down!
Come on, man!
(Swoff)
Move!
(Sykes)
Keep it moving.
Just fucking move!
Come on!
No!
(Sykes)
Keep moving! Don't bunch up!
You can do it!
(Troy)
You can fucking do it!
(Sykes)
Keep moving! Come on!
I can't!
Keep moving!
Don't bunch up!
I can't! No!
Cease-fire!
Corpsman!
Shit!
[Gasping]
Shit.
I told you to keep
your fucking head down!
If you listened to me...
you would still be
fucking alive right now!
Stupid fuck!
[Thunder rumbling]
(Sykes)
God help me.
You are now scout snipers.
Now, I know you've heard this
but I'm going to tell it
to you again:
Snipers do not work alone.
You work as a team.
Spotter, shooter.
You may now open your case,
pull out your M40A1 rifles.
Once you've done that,
you will repeat after me.
This is my rifle.
(all)
There are many like it,
but this one is mine.
Without my rifle,
I am nothing.
Without me,
my rifle is nothing.
(Swoff)
The grunt dies for
15,000 poorly placed rounds.
Fucking right.
The sniper dies...
for that one perfect shot.
[Gunfire]
Hit.
Fire, fire, fire.
I was hooked.
Hit.
Fire, fire, fire.
[Gunfire]
Hit.
I wanted the pink mist.
Good evening.
Iraq invaded and took over...
its tiny neighbor,
Kuwait, today.
That set off
worldwide protests
and drew sanctions...
from the United States,
Great Britain
and the Soviet Union.
The government
of dictator Saddam Hussein...
claimed it went in
at the invitation
of revolutionaries...
who had overthrown
the Kuwaiti government.
We have appealed
to all our friends
around the world...
including
the United States...
to come to our aid
and assistance.
We're going to fucking war.
##[Ride of the Valkyries
playing]
##[Marines singing
Ride of the Valkyries]
# Ta-ta-da-da ##
[all cheering]
(all)
# Ta-ta-da-da ##
[woman speaking in Vietnamese]
Shoot that motherfucker.
[Chattering in Spanish]
[All cheering]
[Marines hooting]
Come on,
start running, motherfucker.
Fuck.
Shoot that motherfucker!
Die!
[All cheering]
Run, Charlie!
[All sighing]
(announcer)
Now hear this. Now hear this.
All personnel from 2-7...
are to report immediately
to your company area.
Get some, Marines. Get some!
[All cheering]
[Marines chattering]
(Kruger)
Me, I had a choice...
either join the Marines
or go to jail.
And you know
what the shit of it is?
Yeah, if you'd
gone to jail...
Don't spoil
the joke, asshole.
If I'd have went to jail,
I'd be getting out today.
Would you like some nuts?
No, thanks.
Yes, are they warm nuts?
No, I believe
they're room temperature.
Well, maybe later
you can come
and warm up my nuts.
You know,
I don't really like
the little ones.
[Chuckling]
Okay, is that all?
Yeah.
(stewardess)
Would you like some nuts?
You poor bastard.
I bet your recruiter
promised you a whole
wide world of pussy, huh?
You fucking A.
Cocksucker knew the price
of every whore
from Olangapo to Stockholm.
And here we are,
headed to the desert.
No pussy in 1,000 miles.
Fucked by
the green wienie again.
What would you be doing
if you were a civilian?
Staying up late,
jacking off...
playing Metroid, trying to get
to that ninth level?
You know what happens
when you get there?
Nothing.
You just start
all over again.
How long you think
we'll be there? Two weeks?
Less, man.
We'll be back so fast...
we'll still be
shitting out those nuts.
Good luck, now.
Goodbye, now.
Want to keep me company
for two weeks?
Goodbye, now.
You don't know
what you're missing.
Yeah, yeah.
Damn!
[Helicopter whirring]
[Inaudible]
[Marines chattering]
Attention on deck!
Take your seats.
Good afternoon, Marines.
(all)
Good afternoon, sir!
Jesus, did you just land
in a war zone
or a funeral parlor?
Good afternoon, Marines!
Good afternoon, sir!
I just felt my dick move.
[All laughing]
For those of you
who don't know me...
I'm
Lieutenant Colonel Kazinski,
your battalion commander.
We are now a part of
Operation Desert Shield.
Now, just north of us...
Saddam Hussein's got
one million Iraqi soldiers.
And some of those boys
have been fighting...
since you were nine
or ten years old.
They are tough.
They will stop at nothing.
They've used nerve gas
against the Iranians
and the Kurds.
Now, here's a picture.
I know
what you're thinking.
You're thinking,
"Let's kick ass
and take names...
"and end this shit
the day before yesterday. "
(all)
Yeah!
But the bureaucrats
have a lot of jawboning to do.
So for now, these Iraqis
who have raped and pillaged...
poor little Kuwait
are not yet in our gun sights.
Our current mission
is to protect
the oil fields...
of our good friends
in the Kingdom of Saud...
until further notice.
And gentlemen,
I'm talking a lot of oil.
A lot of oil.
So you will hydrate,
you will train...
you will adjust
to this desert,
and you'll hydrate some more.
And you will be ready.
You will maintain
a constant state
of suspicious alertness...
and one day soon...
Saddam Hussein is gonna regret
pulling this sorry shit.
(all)
Ooh-rah!
(Fowler)
We're gonna kick
some Iraqi ass!
[Laughing]
What did you say?
We're gonna kick
some Iraqi ass, sir!
Oh, hell, son.
What, you gonna win
the Medal of Honor
all by yourself?
What's the rest
of my battalion gonna do?
(all)
Kick some Iraqi ass!
You know,
I think it's time
for me to retire.
I can't hear a fucking thing!
Kick some Iraqi ass!
Oh, boys,
I just got a hard-on!
[All laughing]
(Fowler)
Man, this defensive
position shit sucks, huh?
We need to get out
of this shit hole soon.
I need to shoot something!
You're gonna get
all you want soon enough.
First to fucking fight!
Yeah. For what?
I've been around
these old white fuckers
all my life.
They got their fat hands
in Arab oil.
The motherfuckers drink it
like it's beer.
That's why we're here,
to protect their profits.
You're full of shit.
He's full of shit.
Who do you think gave Saddam
all his fucking weapons?
We did!
Fuck politics, all right?
We're here.
All the rest is bullshit.
(Fowler)
Yeah.
[Mumbling]
Everyone else
is unpacking, man.
I'm taking a break.
(Fowler)
What you got?
Photos.
She's hot. Yours?
Yes, man.
You better shoot yourself
in the foot...
and get a ticket home...
because Jodies are
gonna be all over her!
[All exclaiming]
Look at her!
Ain't she an animal!
They won't
leave her alone!
That's nice
for a white chick, man.
Thank you, man.
Nice? Come on.
I'd drink a gallon
of her pee just to see
where it came from.
All right, all right,
all right.
This is hardcore right here.
This is close to porn.
Let me see that one.
Let me see.
She's got
a baby fist down here.
Dream on, brothers, dream on.
I'm storing that
for later, man.
I'm storing it for later.
Hey, y'all horny fucks
wanna see a beautiful woman?
Yeah!
Let's see it.
Give it up!
Check this out.
Yeah, boy!
Give it up, give it up.
No, no, no.
Oh, no! Please
don't love me!
Now, tell them
how many tortillas she had
before that picture.
[All laughing]
Hey, she's pregnant, man.
That's why
she's so beautiful, man.
This is what it's all about
right here, man.
[All booing]
Hey, fuck you guys!
Married guys.
I'm telling you, married guys
lose brain cells
by the billions.
If the Corps wanted you
to have a wife...
they would have
issued you one.
Yeah, they would have
Yeah!
No family photos, Swofford?
Hey, can I see
your pictures?
Yeah, sure, man.
Thanks.
Fergus, right?
Yeah.
She have her own clothes?
Well, ain't this cozy as fuck?
You guys get settled in?
(all)
Yes, Staff Sergeant!
Well,
if you're not too busy...
Gas! Gas! Gas!
Right now!
I'm talking about gas!
Let's go! Let's move it!
Come on, guys,
what the fuck are you doing?
Let's go! Get it on!
Right now your dicks
are falling off!
Your skin is bubble wrap!
Let's go! Move it!
You sorry motherfuckers,
I told you, "Don't get lazy."
Didn't I tell you
not to get lazy? Let's go!
Let's go.
What are you doing?
That's your fucking
sleeping bag, you moron!
Let's go!
It's been 30 seconds.
What the fuck are you doing?
Get it on!
You stay ready,
you ain't got to get ready!
You nasty motherfuckers
are so lazy! I told you
to stay on point!
That's 45 seconds!
What you doing?
You better get
your motherfucking ass
in gear!
You gonna be
the first motherfucker
I kick up in the ass.
Get it on!
I'm trying!
They packed mine wrong!
Retarded motherfuckers,
let's go! Put it on!
Let's go! Stop!
Stop it right now!
[Imitating Darth Vader]
Luke.
Come over
to the dark side, Luke.
55 seconds. You're all dead.
And since you're all dead...
I guess you wouldn't mind
taking a little run
in these suits.
Let's go!
##[Bang a Gong playing]
[Swoff panting]
Swofford,
if you don't pick it up...
I'm gonna shoot you
in your fucking foot!
Move it!
(Swoff)
The price of crude oil
has nearly doubled.
President Bush
sends in more troops.
Us, six times a day,
we gather for formation.
Drink it down,
all of it.
And we hydrate.
Now, hold them up.
We patrol the empty desert.
Get down!
And we dehydrate.
[Sighing]
We throw hand grenades...
into nowhere.
We navigate
imaginary minefields.
We fire at nothing.
[Gunfire]
And we hydrate some more.
You will hydrate
till I get full.
There you go.
Hold it down.
Now, hold them up.
[Swoff sighing]
And we look north,
towards the border...
and we wait for them.
This is our labor.
We wait.
I got one! A white one!
Master race.
[Exclaiming]
Check her out.
It's beautiful.
Chango's reign of terror
is over! Over!
[Marines cheering]
Come on!
It's over,
you fucking pussy,
Chango.
Chango, come on.
(all)
Hey, come on, Chango.
Come on, Chango!
[All cheering]
(Fowler)
Now you're gonna see a fight, kid!
Come on! Come on!
[All cheering]
Come on, whitey!
Come on. Come on.
Come on! Come on!
(Fowler)
Pay me my money,
motherfuckers!
(all)
All right!
(Marine)
I told you, I told you!
Go, Chango!
(all)
Chango! Chango! Chango!
[All continue chanting]
Fucking asshole.
(Swoff)
Suggested techniques
for the Marine to use...
in the avoidance
of boredom and loneliness:
Masturbation...
rereading of letters
from unfaithful wives
and girlfriends...
cleaning your rifle...
further masturbation...
rewiring Walkmen...
arguing about religion
and meaning of life...
discussing in detail
every woman the Marine
has ever fucked...
debating differences,
such as Cuban
versus Mexican...
Harleys versus Hondas...
left- versus right-handed
masturbation...
further cleaning of rifle...
studying of Filipino
mail-order bride catalog...
further masturbation...
planning of
Marine's first meal
on return home...
imagining what
the Marine's girlfriend...
and her man Jody
are doing in the hay...
or in the alley...
or in a hotel bed.
Is she up there yet?
What?
Get the fuck off me, man.
Don't worry, she will be.
She'll be right there.
She's gonna look beautiful
up there.
Yeah. Thank you.
I wonder what she's doing
right now.
No way to know.
(Sykes)
Now, here are the rules.
When you talk
to these reporters,
you do not get specific.
Tell them that there's
no better shooters
in the world...
than Marine snipers.
Tell them that you're happy
to be here.
You're proud of the mission.
All right?
And you can't wait to mash
the fuck out of these Iraqis.
Anything other than that
comes out of your mouth...
I get fucked up.
And if I get fucked up,
I'm gonna fuck you up.
(Sykes)
Take your shirts off.
Show your muscles.
You've been working out.
This is censorship.
This is what?
Censorship.
You're telling us what we can
and can't say to the press.
That's un-American.
Yeah, what about
freedom of speech?
The Constitution?
No, you signed a contract.
You don't have any rights.
You got any complaints,
you complain to
Saddam Insane...
and you see
if he gives a fuck.
Why, that's exactly
what Saddam Hussein does.
You're treating us
the same way.
You are a Marine.
There's no such thing
as speech that is free.
You must pay
for everything that you say.
(cameraman)
We're rolling. Sound, speed.
(woman reporter)
You're a Marine
here in Saudi Arabia.
Are you glad to be here?
Oh, yes, ma'am,
I'm glad to be here.
My uncle and my father
served in Vietnam...
so I'm proud to serve
my country here.
I have supreme confidence
in all my leaders...
you know, from my team leader
to my President.
I'm very proud
to serve my country, yeah.
So, who's waiting
for you back home?
Can I give a message
to my brother?
Sure.
Tim, hey. He's gonna get this?
Uh-huh.
Tim! What's up?
I got your letter, man,
and you are a maniac.
[Screaming]
You're crazy.
He'll understand that.
You're a Marine
here in Saudi Arabia.
How do you hope
the Kuwaitis will greet you?
How do you feel
about the Iraqis?
They're the enemy.
Do you have nightmares
about them?
How do you...
[clearing throat]
I love it out here.
This is what I want.
'Cause I count for something.
Back home...
I'd be working some
nowhere job. Nobody would
even know I was alive.
"We burn the fat
off our souls."
Hemingway, he said that.
Who's waiting
for you back home?
[Laughs]
Well, you know,
I have a girlfriend
waiting for me.
Anything you'd like
to say to her?
Yeah, sure. Yeah.
Hi, Kristina.
Here we are.
[Clears throat]
Are you scared?
Yes, ma'am,
I'm very happy to be here.
I love my country.
I miss my parents.
Hey, Mom, hey, Dad.
They're treating me
all right here.
It was an opportunity for me
to defend America...
the country which
has given freedom to me
and to my family.
And it is an honor
to fight for that freedom.
To defend my country...
and to serve my country...
and to learn skills
to eventually
go into law enforcement.
Are you scared?
Look...
I'm 20 years old...
and I was dumb enough
to sign a contract.
I can hear
their fucking bombs already.
I can hear their bombs.
And I'm fucking scared, yeah.
Don't tell my Staff Sergeant,
though, all right?
(woman reporter)
So in case
of a chemical attack...
what provisions
do your men have for that?
This is what we call
the NBC suits.
That's nuclear-biological
- chemical protective suits.
We also have a mask.
This is the M17 A1 mask...
which is fitted
with a drinking tube...
so these guys
can drink from
their canteens...
without taking off
their masks.
Oh, really?
Want to try it?
No, thanks, but can I hold it?
Yeah, sure.
It's heavy.
Yeah, it is.
But you know, we need these
in order to protect us.
They fight with all this
in all this heat?
Yes, they do.
They fight with it and...
As a matter of fact,
let me give you
a small demonstration of that.
Kruger, get rid of the ball.
Get rid of the ball.
Kruger! Get rid
of the fucking ball.
(Sykes)
Ball.
Fuck.
Give me the ball.
All right, listen up, guys,
today is your lucky day.
These reporters want to see
how your NBC suits work.
All right, so we're gonna
continue this little
football game...
in full chemical gear.
[Laughing]
That's right.
Come on, let's go.
It's 112 degrees.
Then I guess
you won't be needing
your parkas, will you?
Let's play!
[Breathing heavily]
[All shouting]
I'm gonna hurt you, Swoff.
I'm gonna hurt you so bad.
Do you like pain?
(Marine #1)
Hut!
(Kruger)
Swoff!
(Swoff)
Where's the fucking ball?
Swofford, what is that?
Swofford, I guess
you call that
using your head, huh?
Using his head.
(Marine #2)
Hut.
[All shouting]
(Marine #3)
Hut!
[Yelling]
[All cheering]
(Kruger)
Cortez!
Fuck you! Fuck you, bitch!
Who got me? Who got me?
No, no, I want him.
You want
the Mexican leprechaun?
Well, let's take him.
Yeah, I'll take
the fucking midget.
I'm the midget?
Let's go,
you squishy-faced retard.
Don't you ever call me
a squishy-face.
Squishy-face.
Let's go, baby, squishy-face!
Let's go, squishy-face.
Motherfucker!
[Marine yelling]
[Whistle blowing]
All right, that's it!
That's halftime!
Put the masks back on.
Bring the water.
We're gonna further
this demonstration.
Men, these M17 A1
drinking tubes...
are designed to work
perfectly with your canteen
and your mask.
Take the narrow part
of the tube...
with your fingers
extended and joined...
and place it into
the appropriate receptacle...
on the canteen lid.
The lid on my canteen's
fucked.
Watch your mouth.
I got another one
for you right there.
(Troy)
My hydration tube is busted,
Staff Sergeant.
We're gonna die
of dehydration.
We're not gonna die.
Just cool it.
Staff Sergeant,
my drinking tube fell off...
at the gas chamber
at Pendleton.
It's been four months...
I understand that,
and I want everybody
to understand this!
Fucking piece of shit!
And I want you to play
fucking ball!
(Marine)
Oh, that's a peach, baby! Go!
[Marines cheering]
Kruger of Arabia!
Kruger, field fuck.
Field fuck?
Field fuck!
It's just good
old American...
##[Gonna Make You Sweat
playing]
Shit.
Stop it. Stop it,
you assholes. Stop it!
(Sykes)
Put your clothes on!
Come on, bring the camera.
You're gonna put
your clothes on
and quit acting like monkeys.
You stupid motherfuckers.
Put your clothes on, assholes!
[All cheering]
(Kruger)
Come on.
Let's go check out
the artillery and everything.
Field what?
He said "field fun."
That's one of the exercises
that we run here in the field.
The armory.
Why don't we have
a look at that?
Yeah, let's...
[all yelling]
[Marines all hooting]
Come back soon, now, you hear?
I don't hear you laughing now.
[All laughing]
I can't hear you.
That's better. Sounds jovial.
Platoon! Atten-hut!
(Sykes)
Lance Corporal Swofford!
Yes, Staff Sergeant!
On top of the world, huh?
Well, I have
more important things to do...
like play with my balls.
But guess what,
you guys are scheduled...
for a little two-day vacation
back in the rear...
so I suggest
you get your shit together.
You can start
by taking all that down.
(Marine)
Fuck!
(Sykes)
Yeah, whatever.
[Thunder rumbling]
(Troy)
Come on, Swoff, pack up.
(Fowler)
Your mommy again, Fergie.
What are you listening to?
(Fergus)
My mom's Christmas tape.
You're a retard.
(Troy)
Fergus, you and your mom
got fire watch tonight.
2200 to 0200.
(Fergus)
Man, that's two
straight weeks.
Why does it have to be me?
(Troy)
'Cause you're so boot.
(Fowler)
You are boot.
Oh, yeah.
That's the third
fucking time, man.
What's that?
I just want it to say
"no preference."
Is that so fucking hard?
What difference does it make?
God knows you're
"no preference."
(Kruger)
At least they got
the blood type right.
I mean, which would you
rather get? The wrong prayer
or the wrong blood?
(Fowler)
One lonely pink letter
from Sacramento.
Kristina. I wonder
what she's up to?
Now, I dare you...
(Fowler)
Go jerk off outside.
(Cortez)
Oh, my God.
(Marine #1)
What?
Oh, my God, man, I have a son!
[All yelling]
I got a fucking son, man!
I got a little boy!
(Marine)
Let's see.
Look at that cute kid.
You better check
the mailman, bro.
This baby's a gringo, man.
No way. That's definitely
Montezuma Jr.
I don't care, as long as
he's not a Cuban
with a little dick.
Cortez, can I see him?
Here you go, Pinko.
He's beautiful, man.
[All cheering]
(Cortez)
I'll put my little boy up.
Doesn't look good.
Kristina has a new friend,
man.
She got a new friend?
He's the night manager
at her hotel, and she says
he's a good listener.
Man! This is getting worse.
He's fucked, man.
Oh, I told you. I told you.
She's one of those girls
with a military fetish.
Yeah, and she's getting off
when she tells the Jody...
that her boyfriend's
a jarhead.
Yeah, man, fuck.
All right, fuck off.
I can see it.
I can see it now.
She works in a hotel.
She goes into
a vacant room, right?
Grabs onto the pole and goes,
"Jody! Jody! Six-foot-four!"
(Troy)
Hey, hey, hey.
Go pull the legs off a spider.
Okay, Corporal.
(Kruger)
Hey, Swoff. That's right.
Cheer up, man.
We heading back to the rear.
We'll get some AC...
shit in a flush toilet,
you can use the phone.
I'm gonna call her.
(Kruger)
You fucking A.
Even if she is fucking
someone else.
Root beer shower!
No more monkey ass!
[All cheering]
Root beer shower!
[Marine hooting]
What? Where are you going?
To work.
Where you going?
Hey, look, it's a cock,
but smaller.
[People chattering]
##[Something in the Way
playing]
[Breathing heavily]
Fuck!
(Kristina)
Hello?
Kris, it's me.
Hello.
[Laughing]
Oh, my God, Tony.
How are you? I'm good.
How are you?
[Laughing]
Missing you.
I'm all right.
I'm missing you, too.
I saw your mom.
We went to visit your sister.
How is she?
Your mom?
No, Rini.
She's doing better.
She's doing really good.
So this guy...
Did you get the pictures?
Yeah, I got them.
They're great.
Did you see the one
of you and me?
The guy at the hotel...
Who?
How well do you know him,
Kris?
Who, Carl? He's just a friend.
How well do you know him?
Tony, he's just a friend.
Hello?
Yeah, I'm here.
Kris?
Tony?
I'm here.
Tony!
Kris?
God.
[Off-the-hook phone beeping]
[Water running]
[Retching]
[Coughing]
You were making
some pretty weird sounds, man.
Dettman's wife sent him
Deer Hunter.
Let's go watch it.
[Coughing]
(Fowler)
Put it on!
Shut up, Fowler,
you fucking shit bird!
Shut the fuck up.
(Dettman)
You shut up already.
(Marine)
Yeah!
##[Deer Hunter
theme music playing]
Get your boot off
my fucking chair,
you fucking boot.
Rude motherfucker, Swoff.
[Groaning]
[All yelling]
What the fuck?
That's my wife.
That's my fucking wife!
Oh, fuck. That's my wife.
That's Clancey.
That's my fucking neighbor.
I lent him my fucking car.
That's my wife.
That's my fucking wife!
[Moaning]
You fucking bitch!
No! You slut! No!
Fuck!
[Crying]
You don't need
to see this shit.
Oh, fuck, baby.
You don't need to see this.
Swoff, come on.
Take him outside.
Come on, Dettman. Come on.
Fuck! I wanna go home!
(Dettman)
I wanna go home.
Who's fucking around now,
Brian?
[All yelling]
Fucking faggot, man!
Let's watch it again!
[All cheering]
[All chattering]
That's enough! That's enough!
(Fowler)
No, no, no! Why?
That's his fucking wife!
[Screaming]
[Marine booing]
No fun!
What are you doing?
I'm waiting for you to leave
so I can watch it again.
Why do you want to
watch it again?
I want to watch it again.
Why?
I want to see
what it's like...
to watch somebody else
fuck your girlfriend.
[Exhales]
Come on. Get your shit.
Come on. We're going back.
(Swoff)
For most problems...
the Marine is issued
a solution.
If ill, go to sickbay.
If wounded, call corpsman.
If dead,
report to graves registration.
If losing his mind, however...
no standard solution exists.
No...
standard...
solution...
exists.
What's up, buddy?
Merry Christmas.
Yeah.
I hear you got some good shit.
Fly, rumor, on winged feet.
Here...
read this.
What is it?
It's a love letter
for the Major.
I write all of his letters.
"Dear sweet Gloria,
I wish I was up in you now...
"with a finger in your ass.
"Love you, Captain Skinboat."
I studied classics
at Dartmouth.
It's a good school.
$40, five gallons.
[Whistling]
Hey, Swoff.
Which way do I mount this?
What does it say?
"Front toward enemy."
Oh, yeah.
Got to be a clue.
Thanks. Sorry.
Fergus, you take
my watch tonight,
I'll pay you back.
(Fergus)
Not again. It's Christmas Eve.
I'll send you out
a fucking tree.
Oh, great, a tree.
Merry Christmas.
##[OPP playing on radio]
# I'll take you
frame by frame it #
# To have y'all jumpin'
shall we sing it #
# O is for Other,
P is for People
scratchin' temple #
# The last P, well,
that's not that simple #
# You down with OPP ##
[yelling]
[All yelling]
# The first two letters
are the same #
# The last is something
different #
# It's the longest,
loveliest, leanest
I call it the leanest #
# It's another
five letter word ##
[all yelling]
[All cheering]
##[Grandma Got Run Over
by a Reindeer
playing on radio]
##[OPP playing on radio]
[All cheering]
Fucking killers!
##[Grandma Got Run Over
by a Reindeer
playing on radio]
Shit!
[Marines yelling]
Shit.
[Marines all cheering]
Oh, shit!
[Flares exploding]
(Swoff)
What the fuck?
Come on! Now!
Let's get some!
[Marines yelling]
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
What the fuck is that?
It's time to do it all!
It's time for me to...
(Fergus)
Sorry, guys. I'm really sorry.
It was my sausages.
Fucker's fucked now.
[Retching]
So do you have all of that
unauthorized beverage
out of your system?
Whose watch was that,
Swofford?
It was mine.
It was yours.
But since you don't know
how to handle
responsibility...
we are demoting you.
You are now a private.
You think you're the only one
that's bored around here?
Because when this war begins,
and it will begin...
I don't want you
covering my ass.
So guess what's next?
(Swoff)
Instructions for the
effective burning of shitters.
The Marine will need
the following:
One metal fence post,
one pair of welder's gloves...
[flies buzzing]
Five gallons of diesel fuel,
and one box of matches.
Hold it right there, Marine.
So you are the fucking idiot
who tried to
burn down my camp.
Yes, sir.
Stick that back in there.
It's already full
of diesel fuel, sir.
I don't care
if it's full of Chanel No. 5.